{
    "subject": "resource/Carter_G._Woodson",
    "predicate": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#comment",
    "object": "Carter Godwin Woodson (December 19, 1875 \u2013 April 3, 1950) was an African-American historian, author, journalist and the founder of the Association for the Study of African American Life and History. Woodson was one of the first scholars to study African-American history. A founder of The Journal of Negro History in 1915, Woodson has been cited as the father of black history. In February 1926 he announced the celebration of \"Negro History Week\", considered the precursor of Black History Month.",
    "human_readable": "The comment about Carter G. Woodson is that Carter Godwin Woodson (December 19, 1875 \u2013 April 3, 1950) was an African-American historian, author, journalist and the founder of the Association for the Study of African American Life and History. Woodson was one of the first scholars to study African-American history. A founder of The Journal of Negro History in 1915, Woodson has been cited as the father of black history. In February 1926 he announced the celebration of 'Negro History Week', considered the precursor of Black History Month.",
    "questions": [
        {
            "score": 0.904183566570282,
            "question": "Why is Carter G. Woodson often referred to as the 'father of black history'?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.8486796617507935,
            "question": "In what century was Carter G. Woodson born?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.8485245704650879,
            "question": "What profession is Carter G. Woodson known for?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.8440953493118286,
            "question": "Which organization did Carter G. Woodson found?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.8402199149131775,
            "question": "When was Carter G. Woodson born?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.7620322108268738,
            "question": "Name three professions that Carter G. Woodson held."
        },
        {
            "score": 0.7265356779098511,
            "question": "What year did Carter G. Woodson pass away?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.6843484044075012,
            "question": "What field did Carter G. Woodson contribute significantly to?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.6293255090713501,
            "question": "What was the significance of The Journal of Negro History?"
        },
        {
            "score": 0.5897916555404663,
            "question": "What event is considered the precursor to Black History Month?"
        }
    ],
    "google_pages": [
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=The comment about Carter G. Woodson is that Carter Godwin Woodson (December 19, 1875 \u2013 April 3, 1950) was an African-American historian, author, journalist and the founder of the Association for the Study of African American Life and History. Woodson was one of the first scholars to study African-American history. A founder of The Journal of Negro History in 1915, Woodson has been cited as the father of black history. In February 1926 he announced the celebration of 'Negro History Week', considered the precursor of Black History Month.",
            "html": "dbpedia_7657_0.html"
        },
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=What was the significance of The Journal of Negro History?",
            "html": "dbpedia_7657_1.html"
        },
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=What field did Carter G. Woodson contribute significantly to?",
            "html": "dbpedia_7657_2.html"
        },
        {
            "url": "https://www.google.com/search?q=What year did Carter G. Woodson pass away?",
            "html": "dbpedia_7657_3.html"
        }
    ],
    "selected_docs": [
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_25.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_28.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_29.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_37.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_40.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_51.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_55.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_61.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_78.txt"
        },
        {
            "file_id": "dbpedia_7657_79.txt"
        }
    ],
    "final_question": "Is true?",
    "responses": {
        "gemma2": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": "```json\n{'output': 'yes'}\n``` \n\n\nLet me know if you have any other queries!  \n"
        },
        "llama3.1": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": "Here is the answer in the form of a structured JSON format:\n\n{\n  \"output\": \"yes\"\n}\n\nExplanation:\nThe triple statement claims that Carter Godwin Woodson (December 19, 1875 \u2013 April 3, 1950) was an African-American historian, author, journalist and the founder of the Association for the Study of African American Life and History. \nWoodson was one of the first scholars to study African-American history. \nA founder of The Journal of Negro History in 1915, Woodson has been cited as the father of black history.\nIn February 1926 he launched the celebration of \u201cNegro History Week\u201d; it was the precursor of Black History Month.\n\nThis statement is supported by the documents provided:\n\n* /Users/stefanomarchesin/Research/fshami/Rag/docs/dbpedia_7657/re-ranker-msmarco/74.txt\n* /Users/stefanomarchesin/Research/fshami/Rag/docs/dbpedia_7657/re-ranker-msmarco/53.txt\n* /Users/stefanomarchesin/Research/fshami/Rag/docs/dbpedia_7657/re-ranker-msmarco/25.txt\n* /Users/stefanomarchesin/Research/fshami/Rag/docs/dbpedia_7657/re-ranker-msmarco/55.txt\n* /Users/stefanomarchesin/Research/fshami/Rag/docs/dbpedia_7657/re-ranker-msmarco/39.txt\n\nAll of these documents mention Carter Godwin Woodson as an African-American historian, author, journalist and the founder of the Association for the Study of African American Life and History. They also confirm that he was one of the first scholars to study African-American history, founded The Journal of Negro History in 1915 (or 1916), and launched the celebration of \"Negro History Week\" in February 1926, which was a precursor to Black History Month."
        },
        "qwen2.5": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": "```json\n{\n  \"output\": \"yes\"\n}\n```\n\nThe provided information in the documents supports the given comment about Carter G. Woodson, including his roles as a historian, author, and journalist; the founding of the Association for the Study of African American Life and History and The Journal of Negro History; and his role as the father of black history, along with his initiative to celebrate 'Negro History Week' in February 1926."
        },
        "mistral": {
            "short_ans": 1,
            "full_ans": " {'output': 'yes'}"
        }
    },
    "need_tiebreaker": false,
    "tiebreakers_responses": {
        "qwen2.5:14b": {},
        "llama3.1:70b": {}
    },
    "final_decision": 1,
    "actual_decision": 1,
    "analysis": {
        "stratum": "Very Popular",
        "topic": "-"
    },
    "errors": {}
}